utsa.edu 2002-12-04

# Privacy Policy for The University of Texas at San Antonio

## The University of Texas at San Antonio Internet Privacy Statement

The University of Texas at San Antonio(UTSA) maintains the UTSA website, www.utsa.edu, as a service to its students, employees and external constituencies.  UTSA has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy and to address concerns about the types of information gathered and how it is used for all pages on the official UTSA site. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website: [www.utsa.edu](http://www.utsa.edu/).

#### 1\. Email and Form Information

If a member of the general public sends an email message or fills out a web-based form with a question or comment that contains personally identifying information, that information will only be used to directly respond to the requestor.  The information will additionally be used in analyzing internet trends within the UTSA domain for future navigation enhancement.  The request for information may be redirected to another part of the University, institution, government agency or person that may be in a better position to respond to the request.

In addition, you are entitled to be informed about the information UTSA. collects about you. Under Sections 552.021 and 552.023 of the Texas Government Code, you are entitled to receive and review this information. Under Section 559.004 of the Texas Government Code, you are entitled to have UTSA. correct information about you that is held by us and that is incorrect, in accordance with the procedures set forth in the University of Texas System Business Procedures Memorandum 32. The information that UTSA. collects will be retained and maintained as required by Texas records retention laws (Section 441.180 et seq. of the Texas Government Code) and rules. Different types of information are kept for different periods of time. 

It should be noted that electronic mail and other Internet communications channels are not necessarily secure against interception.  While we take precautions, such as encrypting communications where appropriate, if your communication is very sensitive, or it includes information such as academic history or grades, you might want to send it by postal mail instead. 

#### 2\. Cookies 

A “cookie” is a small file containing information that is placed on a user’s computer by a web server..  Any information that UTSA may store in cookies is used exclusively for internal purposes only and will not disclose personally identifiable information to outside parties unless legally required to do so in connection with legal proceedings or law enforcement investigations. 

#### 3\. Logs and Network monitoring

For site administration functions, information is collected for analysis and statistical purposes of navigation trends to the UTSA server.  This information is used to help diagnose problems with the server and to carry out other administrative tasks, such as assessing what information is of most interest, determining technical design specifications and identifying system performance and/or problem areas. 

The following is an example of types of information collected for analysis needs:

  1. Hostname:  The hostname and/or IP address of the computer requesting access to the site.
  2. User-Agent:  The user-agent information includes the types and version of a particular internet browser, and the operating system on which it runs.
  3. Referrer:  The web page from which the client accessed the current page.
  4. System Date: The date and time on the server at the time of access.
  5. Full Request: The exact request of the user/client.
  6. Status: The status code that the server returned, e.g.,, fulfilled request, file not found, etc.
  7. Content Length: The content length, in bytes, of the document sent to the user/client.
  8. Method: The request method used by the browser, e.g., post, get.
  9. Universal Resource Identifier (URI): The location of the particular resources requested (URL).
  10. Query String of the URI: Anything after a question mark in a URI. ;
  11. Protocol: the transport protocol and version used., .e.g., ftp, http 1.0, etc. 

The above stated information is not used in any way that would reveal personally identifiable information to external constituencies unless UTSA is legally required to do so in connection with law enforcement investigations or other legal proceedings. 

#### 4\. Security

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under the control of the UTSA web server administrators. 

#### 5\. Links

This site contains links to other sites outside of the utsa.edu domain. UTSA is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites. 

#### 6\. Choice/Opt-Out/Correct/Update

The [www.utsa.edu](http://www.utsa.edu/) site gives users the following option for removing or correcting their information from any publicly posted page i.e., student directory. 

#### 7\. Contacting the Web Site

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact

Web TeamThe University of Texas at San Antonio  
University Communications  
6900 N. Loop 1604 West  
San Antonio, TX 78249
